Ramanuja Magadi Anantha Krishna

ASU, Tempe, 9782593434, anantharamanuja@gmail.com

Professional Profile: LinkedIn, GitHub

PROFILE

Data Science Student with 2 years of experience at Informatica as an product support engineer for the product - Cloud Data integration. skills.

Resolved 950+ customer cases, published knowledge articles, and maintained A+ grades in the Master's program.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

• Associate Software Engineer, Informatica, Bangalore

Oct 2022 - June 2024

- Resolved complex customer issues in Global Customer Support, worked under very critical conditions like the production systems being down, Proof of concept, etc.
- Developed expertise in SQL, scripting, and network mechanisms.
- Collaborated across teams for optimal product deployment.

• Intern, Informatica, Bangalore

Feb 2022 - Oct 2022

- Gained hands-on experience with Cloud Data Integration tools.
- Authored technical articles and videos.

\bullet Front End Developer, Compsoft Technologies, Remote

2022

- Built a CGPA and SGPA calculator for the 2018 scheme to address missing credits and scores in existing online applications.
- Utilized custom formulas to compute SGPA and CGPA, providing students with accurate results in compliance with the latest scheme.

EDUCATION

• Master's in Data Science, Arizona State University, Tempe

Aug 2024 - Present

- A+ Grade in 1st Semester; Experience with Docker, Kubernetes, Kafka, Neo4j, SQL.
- Conducted performance optimization using OpenMP.

• BE in Information Science, Vidyavardhaka College of Engineering

Aug 2018 - Jul 2022

- CGPA: 8.82; Studied data structures, AI, machine learning.
- Programming skills in C++, Java, Python.

KEY PROJECTS

• Graph Exploration of NYC Taxi Trips

Nov 2024 - Dec 2024

- Built a graph analytics platform using Neo4j, Docker, and Kubernetes.
- Implemented real-time data streaming and applied graph algorithms for insights using kafka and Neo4j.

• NYC Taxi Data Processing

Oct 2024

- Processed NYC Taxi dataset for route optimization.
- Utilized Apache Spark, Python, and PostgreSQL for ETL and analytics.

• Air Gesture Keyboard

2021 - 2022

- Published Research Paper on hand gesture recognition achieving 96% accuracy.
- The product recognizes the gestures made in the air and translates it to the corresponding letter, it can be trained in any language, but the testing was performed for english.
- Designed a user-friendly air gesture keyboard system.

• Notable Projects with GitHub Links

- Motion Sensor System [GitHub]
- Police Station Database Management [GitHub]
- $-\,$ Clothing Store Inventory App [GitHub]
- SGPA Calculator [GitHub]
- Shallow Water Equations in OpenMP Parallelized solutions for high-performance computing.
- $-\,$ Contact Application [GitHub]
- $-\ \ Processing\ Subreddits\ -\ Processed\ 4M+\ subreddit\ rows,\ stored\ in\ PostgreSQL,\ performed\ complex\ queries.$

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Technologies

- Informatica, Azure DevOps
- Linux, Snowflake
- Kubernetes, Docker
- Apache Spark, Kafka
- Neo4j, PostgreSQL
- AWS (S3, EC2, Redshift)
- Postman, GitHub

COMMUNITY & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Volunteer for Robinhood Army.
- Marathoner, Duathlon Athlete.
- Key Opinion Leader, Saucony Running Shoes India.
- Organized Barcamp on Leading Technologies.

Programming

- Python
- Java
- C/C++
- SQL
- Shell Scripting
- Neo4j Cypher
- Scala